# **Zackary Santana**

Miami, FL | +1-786-212-6242 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/zackary-santana | zsant014@fiu.edu | https://zackaryjamessantana.com

## **Summary**

5+ years of experience as a self-motivated software developer that focuses on learning better ways to develop and loves to apply new technologies and develop them cleanly and efficiently. Experience with working in a constantly changing development environment with continuous deployment/integration. Loves working on Fullstack, DevOps, UNIX, and Database related work!

### Education

## Florida International University

Expected Graduation: July 2024

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.6

• Advance UNIX Programming, Algorithm Techniques, Artificial Intelligence, Data Mining, Data Structures, Database Administration, Database Management, Human-Computer Interaction, Operating Systems, Software Engineering

## **Work Experience**

Software Engineer Intern

June 2022 – August 2022

## MongoDB Inc.

- Worked on a scrum (agile) team for MongoDB's internal **CI/CD** testing tool, Evergreen (<a href="https://github.com/evergreen-ci/evergreen">https://github.com/evergreen-ci/evergreen</a>).
- Used Golang to create new REST endpoints, manage existing ones, and create middleware.
- Created new functionality that restarts a subset of tests for the user and systematically keeps track of non-restarted and restarted tests for the same test-suite.

Software Engineer Intern

June 2021 – August 2021

## MetLife Inc.

- Managed and maintained a frontend **Angular.js** application that displayed real-time information that was vital for the team.
- Organized the backend Restify that interacted with a MongoDB that pinged endpoints to test status of Java Virtual Machines.
- Engaged in a SAFe Agile team that made use of scrum to keep track with the day-to-day process.

Director of Technology/Code (https://flow.fly.dev)

January 2021 – Present

#### UPE - Development Program

- Created and managed a responsive and adaptive website for an organization with 8000+ members.
- **React.js and Remix.js** were used for Server-Side Rendering (SSR) and caching. **Strapi** was used to implement a custom Content Management System (**CMS**). **Docker** and **Flyctl** were used for deployment.

Workshop Organizer & Judge

August 2020 – Present

### ShellHacks - Hackathon

- Tailor made and hosted workshops for **Florida's largest hackathon**, **ShellHacks**, which has over **50** sponsors like Microsoft, Google, Amazon, and Facebook and **1000**+ participants.
- Guided participants in using **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **React.js**, **Express.js** to start their web-based hackathon projects.

Learning Assistant Intern for Calculus I & Physics I/II with Calculus

January 2020 – Present

## Learning Assistant Program – Florida International University

- Taught in the Math and Physics department assisting in a total of **5 different classes**, with an average of **70+ students**.
- Supervised 40 students through the material each class and held office hours for 1 on 1's with struggling students.

#### **Skills**

Languages: TypeScript, CSS, SCSS, SQL, Python, Java, VisualBasic.net (VB.net), C, C#, C++, Dart, Bash, AWK

Technologies: Git, Docker, Docker Compose, Node.js, NVM, NPM, Remix.js, React.js, Gatsby.js, Angular.js, Express.js, Next.js,

Svelte 3, UNIX, JavaFX, PostgreSQL, SQL, MongoDB, Flyctl

Productivity: Figma, Notion, Microsoft Teams, Trello, Slite

# **Projects**

LinkedHub (Hackathon) January 2022

Miami Hack Week

- Won first place with a chrome extension that extends LinkedIn's native features.
- Improves the user experience for recruiters to view an applicant's GitHub.
- Uses GitHub's graphQL API to retrieve information like projects, contributions, and displays them on LinkedIn.